<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deokgun Park on Deokgun Park</title>
    <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deokgun Park on Deokgun Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for the graduate school</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/graduate-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/graduate-school/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I got an email from a smart undergraduate student who was interested in research. I think his situation might be a common case so here I added my reply in the hope that this can be helpful to other students. Below is the modified email message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been talking with few graduate recruiters and found out that graduate schools don’t offer scholarship unless I am doing PhD or thesis (which I had no idea what that meant). All I wanted to do was to get a masters degree to gain enough knowledge on AI and deep learning and work for companies like DeepMind or Neuralink to bring AGI and ASI to real life. And now I am overwhelmed and lost with what I’m supposed to do. My options are to loan my way through graduate school (but I can’t do that since I am already on a huge debt for my undergraduate school), or get a PhD (this will take me forever and I will never be able to pay my loans back with the stipend), or find a job (until I am able to pay by loans and fund my graduate school but I really want to be on AI). I recently figured out that my major (computer engineering) wasn’t right for me. I decided to switch to computer science but I needed to take more classes so I am switching to software engineering to graduate on time with right the classes.  My mind’s all over the place and I have no idea where to seek help from.  I’m only halfway through the book even though I love it. I have been dying to learn Reinforcement Learning but I haven’t got time even to start searching about the resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much, Dr. Park! I hope you have a wonderful rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below you can find my advice. TLDR, it is okay to get a job if you are on a debt. If you think you are interested in the research, try to study on your own for a year or two. If you are still interested, you can consider a PhD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-answer-to-the-student&#34;&gt;My answer to the student&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, Tomas (Name changed for privacy)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand your position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is my advice.  The choice is yours. There is no right or wrong choice. The choice is based on who you are and in return shapes who you will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to loan my way through graduate school (but I can’t do that since I am already on a huge debt for my undergraduate school),&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The graduate school here must be master’s degree, right. I don’t recommend it, either. You cannot get enough knowledge on AI topic and you don’t have enough time to create a knowledge that will make you attractable hire for companies like Deep Mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or get a PhD (this will take me forever and I will never be able to pay my loans back with the stipend),&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does not take you forever. It is actually somewhat short to do what I describe above. It will pay you back reasonably well if you are successful. But the decision cannot be made solely on financial reward because this financial reward is probabilistic. Better motivation would be the pursuit of knowledge or curiosity. And the reward is auxiliary. For example, you usually do not pursue professional baseball career because most of baseball related careers are not well-paid. Only winner takes it all.(I hope the chance is higher in the CS.) But many still pursue it because they enjoy baseball anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or find a job (until I am able to pay by loans and fund my graduate school but I really want to be on AI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an actually good option. Get a job. Get decent salary and pay your loans.
The trick is that you can study AI on your own with online learning education resource nowadays. This can be sometimes better than what the Master’s degree can offer.
When you study enough and you have a non-trivial question, it will be a good time to pursue PhD. Of course, consult with professors about your question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attending academic conference is a good investment.
Studying alone is actually harder than you might think. You will be busy for the job (actually everyone is busy, right? Even my 9th grade daughter is busy because she has to watch three hours of youtube videos in addition to all the school work and violin and archery practice) and you may find the AI study is not so fun. The good news is that if you don’t like it, you don’t have to do it. It means that you are probably not good fit for the PhD. Don’t worry. You have a job already and you can focus on the software engineering career which can be also very rewarding. According to my opinion, I think about 5% of the people with good school grades are actually good fit for the PhD. The main reason is that we get good grades by learning what others have found. But PhD is about finding new knowledge which is very different from learning what others have found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a summary, I think you have a potential. If you really want to study AI and deep learning now, you can get a PhD now. If you are not sure, it is okay to get a SWE job. If you find that you keep studying on AI and DL for one or two years on your own, you might consider getting a PhD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regards&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deokgun&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use your advisor</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/how-to-use-your-advisor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/how-to-use-your-advisor/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I got an email from a student from HDILab.  I think his situation might be a common case so here I added my reply in the hope that this can be helpful to other students. Below is the modified email message from the student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello Dr.Park,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am trying to implement carracing. I am using a virtualenv python3.5.4. I am trying to run extract.bash using $sudo bash extract.bash. However, it returns&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;” File “extract.py”, line 8, in &lt;module&gt;
   import gym
ImportError: No module named gym” when extract.bash is trying to run extract.py.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is I installed gym and box2d-py too, and yet it shows the import error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ which pip
/home/aishwarya/WorldModelsExperiments/carracing/venv/bin/pip&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ which python&lt;br /&gt;
/home/aishwarya/WorldModelsExperiments/carracing/venv/bin/python&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also tried the solutions given in here and in here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you please help me out with this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below you can find my advice. TLDR, if you have a technical problem. Solve it on your own while producing shareable outcome. If you have a research idea, your advisor can help you evaluate whether it is intractable, already done, or trivial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-answer-to-the-student&#34;&gt;My answer to the student&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, Tomas (Name changed for privacy)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about this. You should check Google or ask other person&amp;rsquo;s in the lab. I think Jane and John might know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry. Debugging this kind issue is common. I myself always deal with this issue. One of the reason, I cannot help is that the reason can be diverse. It is case by case. Therefore it is more important important to know how to deal with these kind of issues than the actual specific solution.  There will be hardly anyone who can solve your technical problem with a clear answer. If you have one you are lucky. But still if you ask to much questions to him, you are actually costing a precious resource to the group which is a bad news for you.  Below are some general advices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use slack general channel. If you send email to one person, the chance is low that  your busy and ignorant professor can help you. If you use slack to post your issue to the entire group, some competent students might help you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make environment simple.
90 Percent of these issues are package version collision.  Virtual env helps but not perfect. In old days I used to format frequently. That&amp;rsquo;s why I use one disk for system and one disk for home directory. Nowadays learning how to use docker will pay you back well in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try to learn generalizable lesson and share it. Most of time, you just fix and forget. You might try stack overflow or Google solution until you fix it. The problem with this approach is that the time you spent on solving this issue does not produce any credit for your work.  While I also sometimes do that, the correct way to handle an issue is that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;first understand the reason of the issue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;create a technical note or blogs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that explains the issue and the solution.  Many people in the lab can benefit your contribution and your technical blog will help building your professional reputation. You need to be accustomed to solve these kinds of issues. It is like growing your muscles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-use-your-advisor&#34;&gt;How to use your advisor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your advisor cannot help you solve your technical issues, where can I use him? One area is when you have a research question. As a graduate student, you will always think the research question or the topic for the next paper. There can be two major pitfalls for setting the research topic.  An academic work is about finding a knowledge that none has found before. There can be two reasons why nobody has done it before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it can be too difficult to do or trivial but not meaningful.  When we think a new idea, I can bet there will be more than 10 people who have thought the same thing. Still the finding the solution might be too difficult.
Time machine, teleportation, or thinking machines are those areas. Those are technologies that people wish but it is very hard to make a progress in those area.  Or more commonly, your topic is slightly general and there can be many approaches to it. However, the topic might be well-known in the community and almost all low hanging fruits are taken already and what remains might be too challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, your problem might be too narrow or trivial or already solved before.
Your advisor is like a guide to the Mt. Everest or a chaperone to the party. He has an experience and background knowledge about the research community.&lt;br /&gt;
Therefore getting a cross check of your idea can be a good use of your advisor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The HDILab culture</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/hdilab-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/hdilab-culture/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Below is HDILab culture. A culture is a principle about how we do everyday things. I hope that our culture shape our group in a productive way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-learn-by-teaching&#34;&gt;We learn by teaching.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every week we will have a paper reading seminar where one student will teach a paper to other lab members. A pizza and a diet coke will be provided. You will have a chance to announce what you are working on nowadays in a friendly environment 30 minutes before the seminar. Currently the seminar starts on Wednesday 12:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After you have done lab seminar, add the slides and all materials into the Google drive here. The goal here is to make it easier for a new lab member to follow what we have done so far.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also write one paragraph abstract for the seminar to summarize what you teach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add your call sign so that we can know who did the seminar.  Students should answer the questions from colleagues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;team-play&#34;&gt;Team play&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are focused hours in the lab where students are supposed to be at the same space and time. The main idea is to have an informal chat, update, questions and answers. The focused hours are currently held Mon, Tue, Wed 10am-2pm at ERB 205.
Don’t be late.
If you think you will be late, report it to the slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sharable-output&#34;&gt;Sharable output&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students are required to maintain a lab journal and project journal
Lab journal is for the general purpose work and project journal is for the project related progress. For example,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I set up the new server or hardware for the-&amp;gt; hdilab journal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I organized the inventory -&amp;gt; hdilab journal&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I replicated the world model -&amp;gt; daivid journal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every work should be recorded and reproducible.
Basically journal is for yourself. But write it well when others have to find something you did. When you accumulate enough work and progress, make them shareable and transferable chunk into three places:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;journal how-to technical note
When you create a new technical note leave a author call sign such as #deokgun so that I can find who wrote what.
If you need to update it, add a call sign and date after the original author.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Example 
Created: #deokgun 01/08/2019
Updated: #sanjay 01/09/2019 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal homepage blog article&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github readme.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We share the open source code and how-to manual as a final output.
We use GitHub as the main archive
As a rule of thumb, I expect 50% of everyone’s time will be spent writing what you have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-to-write-a-journal&#34;&gt;How to write a journal&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the outline neat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you click the View-&amp;gt; Show Document Outline button, it will show you the document outline. Make sure your writing follows the header rule.
There is a shortcut key for selecting the paragraph level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cmd + alt + 1 makes the top level heading
cmd + alt + 2 makes the second level heading
cmd + alt + 0 makes the content paragraph, which is not shown in outline. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Things to do next part&lt;/strong&gt; is important. Your professor reads it often.  Keep it tidy. When something is done, remove. &lt;strong&gt;Update it everyday&lt;/strong&gt;. When you are given new goal, write it there.  Make the thing you are working on now, the first item. Order them in the priority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;communication-is-half-of-your-job&#34;&gt;Communication is half of your job.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your impact will be the multiplication of research and communication of the result.
Try to report the progress whenever there is a progress
Don&amp;rsquo;t wait until your boss ask your progress. Tell him what you are working on now.
 If you meet a barrier or decide to change direction, report it.
When I ask you to do something, I usually expect to hear the progress report in a one or two days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;being-true-to-ourselves&#34;&gt;Being true to ourselves&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot deceive yourself. Being true to yourself is, in my opinion, a very good long-term strategy. For example, if you don’t know during the seminar, acknowledge that you don’t know and ask questions until you understand. Don’t be embarrassed or give up by social pressure. Academy is a few places where being true to yourself is tolerated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other good question to ask yourself is whether you are enjoying the research. Actually according to my experience, research is not for everyone. Probably about 5 persons out of 100 suit the academic life. Because of this, it is perfectly okay if you feel that the graduate study is not what you want to do. I recommend to get a SW engineering job in that case, which actually pays you better and provides better work-life balance. You might feel like a failure to quit the research at first, but if you are true to yourself, you may find it as one of the best decisions of your life later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly I will release you out of the lab if I think that you are not a good fit for the lab as early as possible. How I make that decision? First, I have to acknowledge that it is very difficult decision for me, too. It is not only emotionally difficult but intellectually difficult. Because nobody knows the future, one day the student I fired may get a Nobel prize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to follow the lab culture which is my principle. For me, there are three characteristics for the academic career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;First is &lt;strong&gt;curiosity&lt;/strong&gt;. The desire to know or find the truth is our strongest motivation and rewards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second is the &lt;strong&gt;self-starting&lt;/strong&gt;. This one is related to curiosity. Because you want to know something, you start researching about it. This is usually observed when the student comes to me and ask an advice for something. It is the opposite of waiting for the order from me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Third is the persistence. The journey is long and the rewards are sparse. If you are not persistent, chances are you give up. &lt;strong&gt;Persistence is measured by the shareable output.&lt;/strong&gt; According to my experience, quantity is more important than the quality for measuring persistence. It means if you are producing lots of so-so blog article or technical note and low quality draft of academic papers, you have the persistence. Think about growing academic muscle by writing everyday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft Evolution</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/soft-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/soft-evolution/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Life evolves. The speed of evolution depends on the mechanism of the evolution. The first evolution was based on the random mutation of the genes. It is basically trial and error. But the diversity of the life forms it generated is awesome. I would call it &lt;strong&gt;hard evolution&lt;/strong&gt;. We, humans, are one of the successful life forms with mosquitoes and cockroaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human adopted a new strategy. It was building a more flexible general purpose brain to adapt to the environment. Other life forms also have the brain. But its function was more rigid or hard encoded. You can think how the pocket calculator compares with the smartphone. Both have a similar electronic components namely CPU, memory and I/O devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the general brain, we can do many things that was not possible. But the essential function is learning. In hard evolution, the special variation that worked well leaves the genes. However, in &lt;strong&gt;soft evolution&lt;/strong&gt;, we can learn from others. It basically allows the exponential trial and errors. Nobody can experience all the diverse experience in the world given limited time and energy. Still we can learn from others first using verbal language. This allowed us to transfer knowledge from the nearby persons. The written language allowed it to go beyond the limitation of the space and time of the verbal language. Now what is beautiful about the soft evolution is that the time it takes to evolve has reduced dramatically. The soft evolution happens in the brain circuitry during the life time of the agent while in the hard evolution, the life time of the agent was a single unit of progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this general flexible brain, we are born as rather blank state compared to other animals such as cats and dogs. Of course there are still many innate circuitry which I will talk later. And it takes relatively long time to have a reasonably working program. Interestingly as the amount of the information to function well in the society increases the time it takes to be independent is also increasing. Now it is common in the first world that it takes about 20 to 30 years before one can be independent from the parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said the brain is born as a basically blank state. But still there are innate mechanism to help learn from the parents. Think of the truly blank state agent. We got a continuous stream of image and sound. How we can make sense of the this image? For example, parents talking to the baby might look like a skin colored chunk with a few holes that are constantly moving. One hole continuously changes shape and make a sound (hint: mouth). How can we learn this chunk of image is a mom and the sound is the language which is different from random noise from the street? Epistemology is an old branch of philosophy devoted to this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the innate mechanism is essential for the new born baby to make sense of the world. Let me give you an example. &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.sciencemag.org/content/198/4312/75&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Andrew Meltzoff and Keith Moore found that a baby who was about 7 hours since the birth can still mimic the tongue movements&lt;/a&gt;. It is quite surprising when we think about all the skills to do this. First, the baby has to recognize the human face. Then he has to map the human face he never seen to his face that he never seen himself. Finally the baby has to control the tongue to imitate the expression.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;./img/imitation-in-baby.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;New born baby can imitate the random facial expression. This capabilities an innate mechanism to help learn from others. We should learn from relevant objects such as people and care givers and not from irrelevant objects such as cars or doors.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.sciencemag.org/content/sci/198/4312/75.full.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Image from Science 1977&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe this imitation capability is essential to learn from others. Given blank state, we should not fill this blank with random noise but relevant contents. What will be the relevant contents for the new born baby. Most likely it will be from the parents and caregivers. The imitation mechanism has already filtered irrelevant objects in the world and focused on the human facial expression and followed its motion. This limits the vast space of the exploration to meaningful trajectory that was suggested by human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lessons-for-the-agi&#34;&gt;Lessons for the AGI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the famous &lt;a href=&#34;https://storage.googleapis.com/deepmind-media/dqn/DQNNaturePaper.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DQN paper&lt;/a&gt;, there are experiments for the Atari games. Among many games that showed superhuman performance by the artificial agent, there was one game that showed very poor performance called &lt;strong&gt;Montezuma&amp;rsquo;s revenge&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/0yI2wJ6F8r0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2016/6/9/11893002/google-ai-deepmind-atari-montezumas-revenge&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog explains why the Montezuma&amp;rsquo;s revenge game is particularly challenging&lt;/a&gt;. In a summary, there are too many things that have to be done sequentially such as getting the key, avoid the monster, and go back to the door. The random behavior by the agent cannot explore the vast exploration space in a limited time. In 100 Million iterations, the agent can access only the second stage. This shows the limitation of the random trial and error. I said other animals cannot learn. But I was wrong. They can learn. For example, dogs can learn new trick. They learn by trial and error. They associate behaviors with positive rewards or treats. But things you can learn from this approach is limited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there are three components for the artificial general intelligence. The first is a model. For example, in my &lt;strong&gt;HPM&lt;/strong&gt; theory, the agent predicts the next sensory input with the help from the hierarchy to do the higher-order prediction (chunking). The second is an environment. It provides a source of information. The problem is there are vast space for exploration. Finally there will be many smart tricks such as imitation or &lt;a href=&#34;http://ilabs.washington.edu/kuhl/pdf/Kuhl_2007.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;social mechanism to focus on the human interaction during language acquisition&lt;/a&gt; to reduce this search space effectively by social learning. Our lab tries to build an &lt;a href=&#34;http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/research-in-hdilab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;environment that can provide a testbed for such social mechanism&lt;/a&gt; and study the models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, what will be the next step for the evolution? I think it will be how we can limit the limitation of the brain cell. The brain cell is relatively small and degradable. If we can use our electronic components as a device, it will achieve a step-up in the evolution speed. But more importantly, I think the true power of the next evolution is when the artificial intelligence agent upgrades its own structure. This upgrades will be beyond the human&amp;rsquo;s ability to follow which is called &lt;strong&gt;technical singularity&lt;/strong&gt;. Some would call it &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nrg1921&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;computational evolution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;./img/evolution.svg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;The evolution of the intelligence&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 - Importing</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/08-importing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 12:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/08-importing/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;08-importing&#34;&gt;08 - Importing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can import the following formats via &lt;code&gt;Notable -&amp;gt; Import&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown files with extension: &lt;code&gt;md&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mkd&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mdwn&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mdown&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;markdown&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;markdn&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mdtxt&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mdtext&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;txt&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evernotes&amp;rsquo; exports with extension: &lt;code&gt;enex&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively you could also just put your Markdown notes into the &lt;code&gt;notes&lt;/code&gt; sub-directory into your data directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more notes you are importing the longer it will take, in some cases the interface may freeze until the operation is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newly imported tags will be tagged with a special &lt;code&gt;Import-XXXX&lt;/code&gt; tag, so that you can easily edit them later using &lt;a href=&#34;@note/09 - Multi-Note Editing.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;multi-note editing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 - Multi-Note Editing</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/09-multi-note-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 12:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/09-multi-note-editing/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;09-multi-note-editing&#34;&gt;09 - Multi-Note Editing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;built-in&#34;&gt;Built-in&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some multi-note editing features are built-in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are multiple ways to select notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click&lt;/strong&gt;: you can toggle a note&amp;rsquo;s selection just by clicking it in the middlebar with &lt;kbd&gt;Cmd+Click&lt;/kbd&gt; on macOS, or with &lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl+Click&lt;/kbd&gt; elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shortcuts&lt;/strong&gt;: some shortcuts are provided under the &lt;code&gt;Edit&lt;/code&gt; menu entry for selecting all notes, inverting the selection and unselecting all of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When 2 or more notes are selected a multi-note editor will be displayed in the mainbar, you&amp;rsquo;ll be asked for confirmation for all changes that will mutate the notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the actions you can take on selected note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Favorite/unfavorite them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pin/unpin them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move to trash/restore/permanently delete them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open them in the default app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add one or multiple tags to them. Useful when importing exported Evernote notebooks since the notebook tag is not preserved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove one or multiple tags from them. Useful when editing imported notes, which get automatically tagged with a special &lt;code&gt;Import-XXXX&lt;/code&gt; tag, so that you can easily select them all for multi-editing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced&#34;&gt;Advanced&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need more advanced multi-note editing, like global search &amp;amp; replace, remember that your notes are just plain Markdown files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could open your data directory into your favorite editor of choice and perform the search &amp;amp; replace there, this way you can also use advanced features like regexes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the edits performed with a third-party application will be reflected into Notable immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 - Linking Attachments, Notes, Tags and Searches</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/10-linking-attachments-notes-tags-and-searches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 12:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/10-linking-attachments-notes-tags-and-searches/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;10-linking-attachments-notes-tags-and-searches&#34;&gt;10 - Linking Attachments, Notes, Tags and Searches&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, like when writing a tutorial for a note-taking app 😉, you may need to link to other notes or embed a few attachments. Notable makes this easy for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These special links can also be right-clicked so that you can perform some actions on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;attachments&#34;&gt;Attachments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attachments can be rendered inline, linked to, and linked to via a button. The &lt;code&gt;@attachment&lt;/code&gt; token is used for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;syntax&#34;&gt;Syntax&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;![Icon](@attachment/icon_small.png)
[Icon](@attachment/icon_small.png)
[](@attachment/icon_small.png)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;result&#34;&gt;Result&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;@attachment/icon_small.png&#34; alt=&#34;Icon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;@attachment/icon_small.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Icon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[](@attachment/icon_small.png)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes can be linked to, and linked to via a button. The &lt;code&gt;@note&lt;/code&gt; token is used for this. Wiki-style links are supported too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;syntax-1&#34;&gt;Syntax&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;[Shortcuts](@note/07 - Shortcuts.md)
[](@note/07 - Shortcuts.md)
[[Importing|08 - Importing.md]]
[[08 - Importing]]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;result-1&#34;&gt;Result&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;@note/07 - Shortcuts.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Shortcuts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[](@note/07 - Shortcuts.md)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[[Importing|08 - Importing.md]]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[[08 - Importing]]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tags&#34;&gt;Tags&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags can be linked to, and linked to via a button. The &lt;code&gt;@tag&lt;/code&gt; token is used for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;syntax-2&#34;&gt;Syntax&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;[Basics](@tag/Basics)
[](@tag/Basics)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;result-2&#34;&gt;Result&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;@tag/Basics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[](@tag/Basics)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;searches&#34;&gt;Searches&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searches can be linked to, and linked to via a button. The &lt;code&gt;@search&lt;/code&gt; token is used for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;syntax-3&#34;&gt;Syntax&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;[linking](@search/linking)
[](@search/linking)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;result-3&#34;&gt;Result&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;@search/linking&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;linking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[](@search/linking)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 - Synchronization</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/11-synchronization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 12:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/11-synchronization/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;11-synchronization&#34;&gt;11 - Synchronization&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notable doesn&amp;rsquo;t have synchronization built-in, but you can have your data synchronized across computers just by putting the data directory into a shared folder, like Dropbox/Google Drive/etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way the third-party service will take care of the synchronization.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 - Mobile Editing</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/12-mobile-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 12:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/12-mobile-editing/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;12-mobile-editing&#34;&gt;12 - Mobile Editing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notable doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a mobile app yet, but there are many apps for editing Markdown files already on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you put your data directory into a shared folder, like Dropbox/Google Drive/etc. you could use any of those apps for editing notes or making new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be perfect, especially if you need to change some metadata or add an attachment, but it would be ok most of the times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13 - Collaborative Editing</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/13-collaborative-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 12:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/13-collaborative-editing/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;13-collaborative-editing&#34;&gt;13 - Collaborative Editing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notable doesn&amp;rsquo;t have collaborative editing built-in, but if you put your data directory in a shared folder, like Dropbox/Google Drive/etc. then multiple people can access it and make edits at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just make sure no 2 people are working on the same note at the same time, or some work might get lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is by no means a perfect solution though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14 - Version Control</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/14-version-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 12:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/14-version-control/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;14-version-control&#34;&gt;14 - Version Control&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notable doesn&amp;rsquo;t have version control built-in, but since the data directory is just a regular directory you could make it a git repository and every once in a while take a snapshot of your notes, or perhaps a small script could make commits automatically for you everytime something changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;rsquo;s a big demand for this perhaps support for version controlled notes can be added to Notable itself, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/notable/notable/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt; if you need this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15 - Encrypted Notes</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/15-encrypted-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 12:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/15-encrypted-notes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;15-encrypted-notes&#34;&gt;15 - Encrypted Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notable doesn&amp;rsquo;t support encrypted notes yet, but if you really need this you could make an encrypted image on your computer and put a data directory in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way the third-party program will take care of the encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;rsquo;s a big demand for this perhaps support for encrypted notes can be added to Notable itself, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/notable/notable/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt; if you need this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrapping up 🎉</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/wrapping-up-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 12:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/wrapping-up-/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;wrapping-up&#34;&gt;Wrapping up 🎉&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome, you&amp;rsquo;ve reached the end of the tutorial!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is deleting all these tutorial notes, you can do this one-by-one, using multi-note editing, or you could just trash the whole &lt;code&gt;notes&lt;/code&gt; sub-directory from your data directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback&#34;&gt;Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve reached this far chances are you&amp;rsquo;re considering using Notable as your main note-taking app, that&amp;rsquo;s great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/notable/notable/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; about any issues you may encounter, any features suggestions and generally sharing your opinion about Notable and how we can improve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also find us in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/notable&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;/r/Notable&lt;/a&gt; subreddit. If you want to support me directly I also have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/fabiospampinato&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Patreon page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a wonderful day! 👋&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 - The Data Directory</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/01-the-data-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 12:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/01-the-data-directory/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;01-the-data-directory&#34;&gt;01 - The Data Directory&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data directory is where all your notes and attachments will be stored, it has the following structure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/path/to/your/data_directory
├─┬ attachments
│ ├── foo.ext
│ ├── bar.ext
│ └── …
└─┬ notes
  ├── foo.md
  ├── bar.md
  └── …
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The data directory gives you freedom since your notes are never locked into some sort of proprietary database, all your files use sane formats and are easily accessible and portable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can open your data directory via &lt;code&gt;Notable -&amp;gt; Open Data Directory&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also change data directory at any time via &lt;code&gt;Notable -&amp;gt; Change Data Directory...&lt;/code&gt;, the current content won&amp;rsquo;t be copied over to the new one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can edit your notes/attachments without even using Notable, all changes you make to them will be reflected here instantly. In fact you could also import a Markdown note simply by copying it into the &lt;code&gt;notes&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-features&#34;&gt;Advanced Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data directory allows you to leverage third-party tools to have powerful features like synchronization, versioning and encryption, we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about those in the &lt;a href=&#34;@tag/Advanced&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;advanced&lt;/a&gt; sections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 - The Sidebar</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/02-the-sidebar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 12:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/notes/02-the-sidebar/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;02-the-sidebar&#34;&gt;02 - The Sidebar&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sidebar is where all your notes are categorized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;categories&#34;&gt;Categories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All Notes&lt;/strong&gt;: This section contains all notes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorites&lt;/strong&gt;: This section contains all notes you&amp;rsquo;ve favorited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notebooks&lt;/strong&gt;: This section contains all notes tagged with the special &lt;code&gt;Notebooks/*&lt;/code&gt; tag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tags&lt;/strong&gt;: This section contains all notes tagged with any tag except the special ones: &lt;code&gt;Notebooks/*&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Templates/*&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Templates&lt;/strong&gt;: This section contains all notes tagged with the special &lt;code&gt;Templates/*&lt;/code&gt; tag. These notes won&amp;rsquo;t be displayed in any other category.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Untagged&lt;/strong&gt;: This section contains all notes that have no tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trash&lt;/strong&gt;: This section contains all notes that have been deleted. These notes won&amp;rsquo;t be displayed in any other category.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can create sub-categories in the following sections: Notebooks, Tags and Templates by using nested tags.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
