<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visual Analytics on Deokgun Park</title>
    <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/tags/visual-analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visual Analytics on Deokgun Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 22:17:58 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/tags/visual-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ConceptVector: Text Visual Analytics via Interactive Lexicon Building Using Word Embedding</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/publication/conceptvector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 22:17:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/publication/conceptvector/</guid>
      <description>The CommentIQ UI showing toggleable visualizations such as scatterplot, map, and timeline (left) that enable overview and filtering of comments, as well as an adjustable ranking based on various weighted quality criteria (right).ConceptVector supports interactive construction of lexicon-based concepts. Here the user creates a new unipolar concept (1) by adding initial keywords related to tidal flooding (2). The system recommends related words along with their semantic groupings (3), also shown in a scatterplot (4), revealing word- and cluster-level relationships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting comment moderators in identifying high quality online news comments</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/publication/commentiq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 23:26:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/publication/commentiq/</guid>
      <description>  The CommentIQ UI showing toggleable visualizations such as scatterplot, map, and timeline (left) that enable overview and filtering of comments, as well as an adjustable ranking based on various weighted quality criteria (right).   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallelspaces: Simultaneous Exploration of Feature and Data for Hypothesis Generation</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/publication/parallelspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 10:40:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/publication/parallelspace/</guid>
      <description>The MovieVis tool. Two groups in the movie space have been selected to compare corresponding user distribution. Two movies selected in the upper-center region—One flew Over the Cuckoos Nest (1975) and Amadeus (1984)–and are shown in blue color. Another two movies selected in a lower-center region—Phenomenon (1996) and Twister (1996)—are shown in orange. The highlighted users are those who liked all both pairs of movies (because the group mode is set to common).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>