<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agi on Deokgun Park</title>
    <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/tags/agi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in agi on Deokgun Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/tags/agi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: Mapping the Landscape of Human-Level Artificial General Intelligence</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/mapping-the-landscape-of-human-level-agi.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/mapping-the-landscape-of-human-level-agi.md/</guid>
      <description>This is the paper review of the following paper.
 Adams, Sam, Itmar Arel, Joscha Bach, Robert Coop, Rod Furlan, Ben Goertzel, J. Storrs Hall et al. &amp;ldquo;Mapping the landscape of human-level artificial general intelligence.&amp;rdquo; AI magazine 33, no. 1 (2012): 25-42.
 The field of AGI is chaotic. For 70 years, there were many ups and downs. Still, we don&amp;rsquo;t have a consensus about how we can assess the human-level artificial general intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observational Learning: How I would build AGI</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/observational-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/observational-learning/</guid>
      <description>Human level intelligence test I propose a language acquisition as the test for the human-level intelligence. If we raise baby animals like a human baby, they will not learn human language. They are capability limited. If a human baby is raised in the jungle without any human interaction, they cannot acquire human language. They are environment limited. We can say that the language acquisition is the function of the capability and the environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olfactory learning</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/olfactory-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/olfactory-learning/</guid>
      <description>Olfactory learning Nowadays you hear artificial intelligence or machine learning frequently.
What is the difference between intelligence and learning?
General words such as intelligence and learning are difficult to define. Rather than trying to define, comparing the meanings can be helpful to understand both concepts.
Intelligence is the rules to active actuators according to the sensory input to improve one&amp;rsquo;s wellbeing. Learning is acquiring new rules after birth. In this sense, intelligence does not need learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My intellectual journey</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/intellectual-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/intellectual-journey/</guid>
      <description>Below is adopted from forward in my Ph.D disseration.
 A man&amp;rsquo;s character is his fate. - Heraclitus
 It all began with the naıve and lazy man’s dream. I wanted interesting information to come to me even though I didn’t know if such information existed, and I didn’t search for it. I am lazy but addicted to information. I am also a Maximizer. According to the book The Paradox of Choice: Why More Is Less by Barry Schwartz, a Maximizer is the kind of person who scans all the available cereals in the supermarket and tries to select the best one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution: Hard, Soft, and Computational?</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/soft-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/soft-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Life evolves. The speed of evolution depends on the mechanism of the evolution. The first evolution was based on the random mutation of genes. It is basically trial and error. But the diversity of the life forms it generated is awesome. I would call it hard evolution. We, humans, are one of the successful life forms with mosquitoes and cockroaches.
Human adopted a new strategy. It was building a more flexible general purpose brain to adapt to the environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewards for AGI</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/rewards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/rewards/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Introduce the role of the rewards in reinforcement learning  Use the example of dog training Explain the dopamine Explain the  Introduce an extrinsic rewards  Classic rewards Used in reinforcement learning examples  Atari Alpha Go World model paper   Introduce an intrinsic rewards
 Explain the limitation of the extrinsic rewards  Montezuma&amp;rsquo;s revenge  Explain the mechanism of the intrinsic rewards  How the curious or explorative behavior relates to the intrinsic rewards How to formulate the intrinsic rewards mathematically?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGI Research in HDILab</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/research-in-hdilab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/research-in-hdilab/</guid>
      <description>Hello,
My name is Deokgun Park and I lead Human Data Interaction Lab (HDILab) in the Department of Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering at the University of Texas at Arlington. In this article, I will explain the problems we are solving at HDILab. In Human Data Interaction Lab, we are studying artificial general intelligence (AGI).
Many students already have an idea about artificial intelligence (AI). But artificial general intelligence or AGI might be a new term.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>