<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agi on Deokgun Park</title>
    <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/tags/agi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in agi on Deokgun Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/tags/agi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewards for AGI</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/rewards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/rewards/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Introduce the role of the rewards in reinforcement learning  Use the example of dog training Explain the dopamine Explain the  Introduce an extrinsic rewards  Classic rewards Used in reinforcement learning examples  Atari Alpha Go World model paper   Introduce an intrinsic rewards
 Explain the limitation of the extrinsic rewards  Montezuma&amp;rsquo;s revenge  Explain the mechanism of the intrinsic rewards  How the curious or explorative behavior relates to the intrinsic rewards How to formulate the intrinsic rewards mathematically?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft Evolution</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/soft-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/soft-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Life evolves. The speed of evolution depends on the mechanism of the evolution. The first evolution was based on the random mutation of genes. It is basically trial and error. But the diversity of the life forms it generated is awesome. I would call it hard evolution. We, humans, are one of the successful life forms with mosquitoes and cockroaches.
Human adopted a new strategy. It was building a more flexible general purpose brain to adapt to the environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGI Research in HDILab</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/research-in-hdilab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/research-in-hdilab/</guid>
      <description>Hello,
My name is Deokgun Park and I lead Human Data Interaction Lab (HDILab) in the Department of Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering at the University of Texas at Arlington. In this article, I will explain the problems we are solving at HDILab. In Human Data Interaction Lab, we are studying artificial general intelligence (AGI).
Many students already have an idea about artificial intelligence (AI). But artificial general intelligence or AGI might be a new term.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>