<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agi on Deokgun Park</title>
    <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/tags/agi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in agi on Deokgun Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/tags/agi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: Online learning and generalization of parts-based image representations by non-negative sparse autoencoders</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/nnsae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/nnsae/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents an online autoencoder that produces non-negative sparse embedding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: Universal Intelligence: A Definition of Machine Intelligence</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/universal-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/universal-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>This paper defines intelligence as an agent&amp;rsquo;s ability to achieve goals in a wide range of environments. And authors present elegant mathematical formulation based on the concept of rewards and Kolmogorov complexity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture Summary: AI-Horizons Colloquium by Yoshua Bengio</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/yoshua-bengio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/yoshua-bengio/</guid>
      <description>This lecture summarizies the current challenge of Deep Learning and a few approaches by Yoshua Bengio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: An Immersive System for Browsing and Visualizing Surveillance Video</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/housefly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/housefly/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents HouseFly, which is an immersive video analytics platform where 3 years of videos from multiple camera can be shown as immersive video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: A cortical sparse distributed coding model linking mini- and macrocolumn-scale functionality</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/sparsey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/sparsey/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents Sparsey model which uses sparse distributed coding or representation (SDR) to build a hierarchical classifier. The main idea is using familarity to control the randomness of representation. But the simplication poses limited applicability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: AGI Preschool: A Framework for Evaluating Early-Stage Human-like AGIs</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/preschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/preschool/</guid>
      <description>The main idea is using an environment that resembles a preschool. I think it is an improvement over other tests such as Turing test, College Student test, or 8th grader test. But it still does not answer how the agent acquire communication skill using human language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: Mapping the Landscape of Human-Level Artificial General Intelligence</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/mapping-the-landscape-of-human-level-agi.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/mapping-the-landscape-of-human-level-agi.md/</guid>
      <description>This paper shows an overview of AGI capabilities from developmental psychology, mathematical, physiological, and information processing perspectives. Also it discusses how to evaluate AGI using environments, tasks, and scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observational Learning: How I would build AGI</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/observational-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/observational-learning/</guid>
      <description>Below I summarize my plan for building artificial general intelligence (AGI). I start with the test for AGI, and then goes into environments and models for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olfactory learning</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/olfactory-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/olfactory-learning/</guid>
      <description>Intelligence is the rules to actuate actuators according to sensory input to improve one&amp;rsquo;s well-being. Learning is acquiring new rules after birth. Learning requires sensors, actuators, and memory. Olfactory learning is the first learning that can give insight to the minimum parts for learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My intellectual journey</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/intellectual-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/intellectual-journey/</guid>
      <description>I was lazy and news-addict that I wanted news story that suits my interest flows towards me. I started with recommender system but soon found that it cannot deal with the delicacy of human language. I studied visual analytics to combine human intelligence with machine learning for the text analysis. But still found it unsatisfactory. Now I am studying grounded language which lead to artificial general intelligence research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution: Hard, Soft, and Computational?</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/soft-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/soft-evolution/</guid>
      <description>The first evolution mechanism was based on the DNA. The second evolution mechanism was based on the brain. The third  evolution mechanism will be based on algorithms</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewards for AGI</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/rewards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/rewards/</guid>
      <description>Extrinsic rewards is for the animal or bug level of intelligence. Intrinsic rewards or curiosity enables efficient navigation in the vast exploration space. Social rewards enable imitation or gated learning which reduces the exploration space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGI Research in HDILab</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/research-in-hdilab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/research-in-hdilab/</guid>
      <description>Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) Research at Human Data Interaction Lab (HDILab)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>