<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>model on Deokgun Park</title>
    <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/tags/model/</link>
    <description>Recent content in model on Deokgun Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/tags/model/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: Online learning and generalization of parts-based image representations by non-negative sparse autoencoders</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/nnsae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/nnsae/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents an online autoencoder that produces non-negative sparse embedding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: Universal Intelligence: A Definition of Machine Intelligence</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/universal-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/universal-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>This paper defines intelligence as an agent&amp;rsquo;s ability to achieve goals in a wide range of environments. And authors present elegant mathematical formulation based on the concept of rewards and Kolmogorov complexity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture Summary: AI-Horizons Colloquium by Yoshua Bengio</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/yoshua-bengio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/yoshua-bengio/</guid>
      <description>This lecture summarizies the current challenge of Deep Learning and a few approaches by Yoshua Bengio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: A cortical sparse distributed coding model linking mini- and macrocolumn-scale functionality</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/sparsey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/sparsey/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents Sparsey model which uses sparse distributed coding or representation (SDR) to build a hierarchical classifier. The main idea is using familarity to control the randomness of representation. But the simplication poses limited applicability.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>