<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Deokgun Park</title>
    <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Deokgun Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for the master students who want to do reserach in my lab</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/master-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/master-research/</guid>
      <description>I get many emails from master students who are interested in reserach.
 I would like to get research experience in my lab. May I join your lab as a master student?
 Below you can find my advice. TLDR, if you plan to pursue PhD after your master, it might be a good idea to experience research in my lab. If you plan to industry career, it might not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for the undergraduate students who consider the graduate school</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/graduate-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/graduate-school/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I got an email from a smart undergraduate student who was interested in research. I think his situation might be a common case so here I added my reply in the hope that this can be helpful to other students. Below is the modified email message.
 I have been talking with few graduate recruiters and found out that graduate schools don’t offer scholarship unless I am doing PhD or thesis (which I had no idea what that meant).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use your advisor</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/how-to-use-your-advisor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/how-to-use-your-advisor/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I got an email from a student from HDILab. I think his situation might be a common case so here I added my reply in the hope that this can be helpful to other students. Below is the modified email message from the student.
 Hello Dr.Park,
I am trying to implement carracing. I am using a virtualenv python3.5.4. I am trying to run extract.bash using $sudo bash extract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The HDILab culture</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/hdilab-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/hdilab-culture/</guid>
      <description>Below is HDILab culture. A culture is a principle about how we do everyday things. I hope that our culture shape our group in a productive way.
We learn by teaching. Every week we will have a paper reading seminar where one student will teach a paper to other lab members. A pizza and a diet coke will be provided. You will have a chance to announce what you are working on nowadays in a friendly environment 30 minutes before the seminar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewards for AGI</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/rewards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/rewards/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Introduce the role of the rewards in reinforcement learning  Use the example of dog training Explain the dopamine Explain the  Introduce an extrinsic rewards  Classic rewards Used in reinforcement learning examples  Atari Alpha Go World model paper   Introduce an intrinsic rewards
 Explain the limitation of the extrinsic rewards  Montezuma&amp;rsquo;s revenge  Explain the mechanism of the intrinsic rewards  How the curious or explorative behavior relates to the intrinsic rewards How to formulate the intrinsic rewards mathematically?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft Evolution</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/soft-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/soft-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Life evolves. The speed of evolution depends on the mechanism of the evolution. The first evolution was based on the random mutation of genes. It is basically trial and error. But the diversity of the life forms it generated is awesome. I would call it hard evolution. We, humans, are one of the successful life forms with mosquitoes and cockroaches.
Human adopted a new strategy. It was building a more flexible general purpose brain to adapt to the environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGI Research in HDILab</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/research-in-hdilab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/research-in-hdilab/</guid>
      <description>Hello,
My name is Deokgun Park and I lead Human Data Interaction Lab (HDILab) in the Department of Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering at the University of Texas at Arlington. In this article, I will explain the problems we are solving at HDILab. In Human Data Interaction Lab, we are studying artificial general intelligence (AGI).
Many students already have an idea about artificial intelligence (AI). But artificial general intelligence or AGI might be a new term.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>