<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>environment on Deokgun Park</title>
    <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/tags/environment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in environment on Deokgun Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/tags/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: Universal Intelligence: A Definition of Machine Intelligence</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/universal-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/universal-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>This paper defines intelligence as an agent&amp;rsquo;s ability to achieve goals in a wide range of environments. And authors present elegant mathematical formulation based on the concept of rewards and Kolmogorov complexity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture Summary: AI-Horizons Colloquium by Yoshua Bengio</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/yoshua-bengio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/yoshua-bengio/</guid>
      <description>This lecture summarizies the current challenge of Deep Learning and a few approaches by Yoshua Bengio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: An Immersive System for Browsing and Visualizing Surveillance Video</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/housefly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/housefly/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents HouseFly, which is an immersive video analytics platform where 3 years of videos from multiple camera can be shown as immersive video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: AGI Preschool: A Framework for Evaluating Early-Stage Human-like AGIs</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/preschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/preschool/</guid>
      <description>The main idea is using an environment that resembles a preschool. I think it is an improvement over other tests such as Turing test, College Student test, or 8th grader test. But it still does not answer how the agent acquire communication skill using human language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Summary: Mapping the Landscape of Human-Level Artificial General Intelligence</title>
      <link>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/mapping-the-landscape-of-human-level-agi.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://crystal.uta.edu/~park/post/mapping-the-landscape-of-human-level-agi.md/</guid>
      <description>This paper shows an overview of AGI capabilities from developmental psychology, mathematical, physiological, and information processing perspectives. Also it discusses how to evaluate AGI using environments, tasks, and scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>